# **DIOMIDES MAVROYIANNIS**

TECHNICALLY ASTUTE ECONOMIST WITH INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

+33 695669809 | dmavroyiannis8@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/diomavro French et Cypriot

Doctorate in Economics with proven experience (over 1 billion euros in value added) and strong practical experience in financial analysis, data analysis and forecasting. Academic background focused on the economics of innovation and pricing using growth maximizing techniques.

# QUALIFICATIONS

#### UNIVERSITE PARIS DAUPHINE

Doctorate in Economics - 2019

- Specialised in industrial organisation, microeconomics and Ergodic economics.
- Thesis focused on the economics of innovation and pricing of intellectual property using growth maximization techniques.
- Doctoral courses in Incentive Mechanism Theory, Advanced Microeconomics, Cooperative Game Theory and History of Economic Thought.
- Published paper: 'Microfoundations of discounting' in Decision Analysis.

#### UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH

MSc in Economics - 2015

- Deepening of technical knowledge in econometrics, micro/macroeconomics and time series. Case studies applied to issues of corporate strategy, investments and mergers-acquisitions.
- Thesis: What is the effect of technology on wages? The main findings are that, as long as humans have the edge on some sectors, the cost disease entails higher overall wages.

# UNIVERSITY OF DURHAM

MSc in International Finance - 2013

- Study of international finance and corporate governance practices alongside econometric techniques for finance and asset pricing (Black Scholes/VAR); international trade and monetary theory.
- Summer school in Cologne. Contributed to a study on the impact of Brazilian tax rates on DHL's supply chains.

#### UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX

BSc Finance - 2012

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## ExxonMobil, Budapest

CORPORATE REPORTING ADVISOR - 08.21 - PRESENT

- Manage reporting units in Norway and UK. Responsible for sales figures and their presentation to management.
- Creation of "tableau" dashboards to automate data processing from SAP to DATAFLEX
- Responsible for the Forex effects on the European region's profits.
  Oversight and innovation of transactional and translational processes for all European revenues.

# Milestone Institute, Budapest

MODULE AND ECON-COHORT LEADER - 08.21 - PRESENT

- Lecturer in Industrial Organization and Econometrics
- Mentor: personalized follow-up, deepening of knowledge and skills for each student, organization of a reading and debate workshop.

# Schuman Associates, Brussels European Economics, Paris

ECONOMIC CONSULTANT - 01.20 - PRESENT

- Counterfactual scenario studies (with and without government subsidies) based on NPV and WACC of innovative projects led by companies in the energy sector (electricity, gas, hydrogen).
- Scale optimization of projects benefiting from government subsidies.
  Grants ranging from 55M € for SMEs to 600M € for multinationals.
- Writing of reports for the European Commission supporting applications for IPCEI grants by European energy companies.
- Prepared the portfolio of numerous projects including market analysis before and post intervention.

### Université Paris Dauphine, Paris Université Marne-la-Vallée, Paris

TEACHING ASSISTANT - 2015 - 2019

- Lecturer: Economics of Uncertainty (VnM, Bayesian, insurance, etc) L3 in Mathematics; General Equilibrium L2 in Mathematics; Microeconomics L1 in Economics.
- Lecturer: Monetary Economics (central banking, interest rates, monetary aggregates); Social and Economic Policies (unemployment, taxation) L2 in Economics.
- Chief librarian for the MSc and PHD library

#### LOGICOM GROUP, Nicosia

CREDIT ANALYST - 2013 - 2014

• Evaluation of credits and associated risks (regressions, probabilistic models). Analysis of the company's internal data and presentations to the economic director and financial analysts.

#### Council of the EU, Brussels

MULTI-ANNUAL FINANCIAL FRAMEWORK ANALYST - 2012 - 2013

- Assisted in the creation of the first draft of a MFF compromise to meet the diverse demands of numerous European Union member states.
- Researched and analysed the effectiveness of various policies, especially direct payment versus conditional payments and the European cohesion fund and it's thresholds.

# **DIOMIDES MAVROYIANNIS**

TECHNICALLY ASTUTE ECONOMIST WITH INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

+33 695669809 | dmavroyiannis8@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/diomavro French and Cypriot

#### IT SKILLS

EXCEL (VBA) | MATHEMATICA | PYTHON STATA | R | EVIEWS | TABLEAU | SAP

#### LANGUAGES

FRENCH, ENGLISH, GREEK - FLUENT HUNGARIAN- LEVEL 1

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Speaker: University of Cyprus Economics Seminar, Cyprus - 2019

**Speaker:** Public Economic Conference, France - 2019

Speaker: Spain-Italy-Netherlands Meeting on Game Theory (SING15), Finland- 2019

Attendee: Real World Risk Institute, New York, USA - 2019

• An intensive workshop run by Nassim Nicholas Taleb which focuses on the statistical properties of fat tails.

Speaker: BiGSEM Workshop in Economic Theory, Germany - 2018

Attendee: NEComplex Systems Institute Summer School, Boston, USA - 2018

• A summer school at MIT run by Yaneer Bar Yam which focuses on complexity science. Included two projects: the first was a python program which could randomly generate fractals of different kinds and the second, also a Python project was about representing communication dynamics on a network with agents who reinforce their opinions by sharing similar information.

Participant: Durham Trading competition, UK - 2012

• A program run over a semester at Durham where masters students compete to get the best outcomes on a trading account. I won 2nd place among around 200 participants, this was partially evaluated using the Sharpe Ratio.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES AND INTERESTS

- Various international experiences:
  - English-French translator in China;
  - Cooperation with the Lebanese teams of Logicom in the creation of a marketing software
  - Military service in Cyprus.
- Avid reader in philosophy and history.

#### REFERENCES UPON REQUEST

- Anthoulis Papachristoforou Group CFO at Logicom Public LTD
  - o a.papachristoforou@logicom.net
- David Ettinger Professor of Economics, Laboratoire d'Economie de Dauphine
  - o david.ettinger@dauphine.psl.eu
- Frédéric Loss Senior Lecturer, Laboratoire d'Economie de Dauphine
  - frederic.loss@dauphine.psl.eu